So far, you've been writing code within the Udacity classroom,
到目前为止 你一直在优达学城的教室
in an environment that looks like this,
这样的环境中编写代码
but you're also going to want to be able to
但你可能也希望能够
run your programs locally on your own computer.
在你自己的计算机上本地运行程序
And this brings up another important difference between Python and C++.
在这里 我们要说一下 Python 和 C++ 之间的另一个重要区别
You learned about the first major difference at the beginning of the last lesson.
在上节课开始时 你就学到了第一个主要区别
And that's that Python is dynamically typed while C++ is statically typed,
那就是 Python 是动态类型的 而 C++ 是静态类型的
which is why I have to write words like int.
这就是为什么我要写像 int 一样的编码
Another major difference is that Python is what's called an interpreted language,
另一个主要区别是 Python 是所谓的解释语言
whereas C++ is a compiled language.
而 C++ 是一种编译语言
The thing is when you write code in Python or C++,
当你用 Python 或者 C++ 编写代码的时候
the computer can't understand directly what you've written.
电脑无法直接了解你所写的内容
The code first needs to be translated into
代码首先需要翻译成
a language the computer understands in Python code,
计算机理解的语言 在 Python 代码中
there's a translator, also known as an interpreter,
有一种翻译器 也被称为解释器
that goes line by line, first,
它会逐行翻译
translating and then executing each line of code.
然后执行每行代码
Translate this line, execute it.
翻译这行 然后执行
This process of translate execute happens until you've reached the end of the file,
这个翻译执行过程一直到你到达文件末尾为止
or in this case, the end of the code cell.
在本例中 一直到代码单元的结尾
And running the cell, behaves as expected.
并运行单元格 按预期的方式运行
The reality is a bit more complex than what I've described,
现实比我所描述的要复杂得多
but this is the general gist of an interpreted language like Python.
但这是 Python 这样的解释语言的基本特征
With a compiled language like C++,
使用 C++ 等编译性语言时
all of the code is translated into a language
所有的代码在被执行前
the compiler can understand before any of it is executed.
都被翻译成一种编译器可以理解的语言
And this step is called compilation.
这一步称为编译
Only after the program has been compiled,
程序只有在编译之后
can it later be executed or run.
才可以被执行或运行
And up until now, we've been hiding this compilation step from you.
到目前为止 我们一直没有向你展示这个编译步骤
When you've written code in the browser,
当你在浏览器中编写代码
and then scroll down,
然后向下滚动
and pressed test run,
并点击测试运行时
we've been secretly compiling and then executing the code in the background.
我们一直在秘密地编译 然后在后台执行代码
So the language has felt interpreted to you up until now.
所以到目前为止 这种语言已经被编译了
But, when you write C++ code on your own computer,
但是 当你在自己的计算机上编写 C++ 代码时
you're going to have to do the compilation step yourself.
你就得自己编译了
And let me show you what that looks like on my computer.
让我向大家展示一下 在我电脑上是如何运行的
Here, I've got that same file,
在这里 我有同样的文件
I call it demo.cpp.
我把它称为 demo.cpp
And if I actually want to run this code on my computer,
如果我真的想在我的电脑上运行这个代码
I have to first pull-up something called a terminal.
我必须先拉起一个叫终端的东西
And don't worry too much about what this terminal is for now.
现在不用纠结什么是终端
The only thing I want to show you is that when I type LS,
你现在只需要知道当我输入 LS
which is a command to list all the files in my current directory,
这个命令时 它会列出我当前目录中所有文件
the only thing I see is this dem.cpp for now.
现在 我看到只有这个 dem.cpp 文件
So, now before I can run this code,
现在我在运行这段代码之前
I need to first compile it.
需要先进行编译
And for my computer,
在我的电脑上
I do that by typing g++ followed by the file name.
我先输入 g++ 然后再输入文件名
In this case, demo.ccp.
在本例中 输入 demo.ccp
I hit enter, and nothing happens.
然后按 Enter 键 结果程序没有反应
But, if I do another LS,
不过 如果我输入另外一个 LS
I now see this second file called a.out.
我可以看见第二个名为 a.out 的文件
And this is a translated or compiled version of the code in demo.ccp.
这是 demo.ccp 中代码的翻译或编译版本
If I type./a.out, and hit enter,
如果我输入 /a.out 然后按 Enter 键
I get exactly the output I was hoping for.
就得到了想要的结果
In the rest of this lesson,
在本课程剩余时间
you're going to learn more about compilation,
你会学习更多关于编译的知识
and we'll start working with C++ code on your own computer.
然后你会在自己的电脑上开始使用 C++ 代码